One convenience in using keywords to
get tasks done is the ease of getting
an opposite of a criterion. Take a look at this
query, which has person information, and the
query has a WHERE clause to only show people
from Los Angeles. I will execute this query,
and we see 91 rows. However, what if we wanted
to see everyone outside of Los Angeles? We
certainly do not want to have to account for
every other possible city in the recordset.
In most cases, we can use the word NOT to
get the opposite of an existing criterion.
Here is the tricky part, though. Watch what
happens when I put the word NOT in front of
the equals sign and execute this query. It does
not work. What needs to happen is that the NOT
needs to be in front of the entire criterion of
City = Los Angeles. I will put the keyword there,
execute the query, and now we see everyone
outside of Los Angeles. Just think opposites
in terms of when to use the NOT keyword, and
you will be successful in using the NOT keyword.